<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
      <title>Jake Goldsborough - changelog</title>
      <link>https://jakegoldsborough.com</link>
      <description></description>
      <generator>Zola</generator>
      <language>en</language>
      <atom:link href="https://jakegoldsborough.com/tags/changelog/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
      <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
      <item>
          <title>2025 - A Review</title>
          <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Unknown</author>
          <link>https://jakegoldsborough.com/blog/2025/yearly-summary/</link>
          <guid>https://jakegoldsborough.com/blog/2025/yearly-summary/</guid>
          <description xml:base="https://jakegoldsborough.com/blog/2025/yearly-summary/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;2025-yearly-recap&quot;&gt;2025 Yearly Recap&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-year-of-building-shipping-and-showing-the-work&quot;&gt;A Year of Building, Shipping, and Showing the Work&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2025 was the year things stopped being ideas in progress and started
becoming systems with gravity. Across code, writing, travel, and
creative work, the through-line was consistency: small, composable
pieces that add up to something durable.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pace was intentional. Ship in public. Measure lightly. Let
curiosity decide what compounds.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;open-source-and-engineering&quot;&gt;Open Source and Engineering&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was a deeply technical year, but not driven by framework churn.
It was about foundations.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Continued deep investment in Rust, especially for CLI and TUI tooling&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multiple self-authored tools reached real usability:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Static resume generation&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Budgeting and finance tooling&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Audio and scrobbling infrastructure&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strong preference for:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Plain data formats&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deterministic builds&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Git as a source of truth&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clear move away from &quot;just ship JSON&quot; toward intentional data modeling&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alongside that:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Declarative systems (NixOS, Docker Compose, reproducible infra)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CLI-first design, with UI as a layer rather than a dependency&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Energy-aware and sustainability-minded technical choices&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A recurring pattern this year: build tools you actually want to use,
then refine them until they feel obvious.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;writing-blogging-and-metrics&quot;&gt;Writing, Blogging, and Metrics&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2025, the blog stopped feeling like a side project and started acting
like a signal.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Consistent long-form technical writing&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multi-part series and deep dives&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Willingness to publish unfinished thinking and iterate publicly&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The results were quiet but meaningful:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Organic traffic from multiple search engines&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Readers arriving via GitHub, chat tools, and RSS&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Early signs of compounding interest rather than spikes&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Metrics stayed in their place: feedback, not validation.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;travel-and-perspective-shifts&quot;&gt;Travel and Perspective Shifts&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Travel this year was less about movement and more about recalibration.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time spent in Europe, especially Central Europe, reinforced:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A preference for walkable cities&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Public transit that works&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Slower, more deliberate daily rhythms&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It also sharpened longer-term thinking around relocation, digital-nomad
feasibility, and how much infrastructure is actually needed to live
well.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This wasn&#x27;t escapism. It was alignment.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;disc-golf-outdoors-and-sustainability&quot;&gt;Disc Golf, Outdoors, and Sustainability&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disc golf remained a grounding constant.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not just as a hobby, but as:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A recurring design constraint (maps, data, APIs)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A sustainability touchstone&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A reminder that systems should work outside, not just on screens&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The focus subtly shifted from collecting and optimizing toward
understanding spaces:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Courses as designed environments&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flow, access, and maintenance&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How technology can support, not dominate, physical experiences&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;creative-work-beyond-code&quot;&gt;Creative Work Beyond Code&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2025 also made room for making things with your hands.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pottery experiments&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tufting and material exploration&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Visual identity and logo work&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These fed back into engineering work by reinforcing:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Process over output&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Material constraints&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Iteration without metrics&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That cross-pollination showed up everywhere.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;career-and-direction&quot;&gt;Career and Direction&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Professionally, this was a year of alignment.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The focus moved further toward:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open-source adjacent work&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tooling that empowers communities&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Infrastructure that disappears when it works&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rather than chasing titles or hype, the emphasis stayed on:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Taste&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maintainability&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Systems that still make sense six months later&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The result was confidence rooted in practice, not positioning.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-shape-of-things-going-forward&quot;&gt;The Shape of Things Going Forward&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If 2024 was about exploration, 2025 was about integration.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is now:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A coherent technical stack&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A public body of work&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clear values around sustainability, simplicity, and ownership&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most importantly, the year ends with momentum that feels calm rather
than frantic.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is the kind that lasts.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      <item>
          <title>ChatGPT assisted Changelog - 42&#x2F;52</title>
          <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Unknown</author>
          <link>https://jakegoldsborough.com/blog/2025/weekly-summary-42/</link>
          <guid>https://jakegoldsborough.com/blog/2025/weekly-summary-42/</guid>
          <description xml:base="https://jakegoldsborough.com/blog/2025/weekly-summary-42/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AWS SDK Ruby contributions and follow-up&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You published &lt;em&gt;Contributing to AWS SDK Ruby - Part 3&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, which wrapped up your series
about improving the Ruby AWS SDK. You mentioned the post got 3 boosts on Mastodon
and linked to it from Hachyderm. We also talked briefly about your earlier PRs and
how they connect -- adding a feature first, then fixing a bug.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Transit Tracker and Discourse experiments&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You released and shared &lt;em&gt;Building a Live Transit Departure Board with Discourse&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;,
a creative exploration of using Discourse for something non-forum-like. We talked
about whether posting it on Discourse&#x27;s official blog or community site would be
weird, and you decided it&#x27;d actually fit since you work there. You also added
screenshots later to make the post more engaging.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GoatCounter and analytics debugging&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You tried exporting page-view data from your self-hosted GoatCounter instance, but
ran into a network failure while testing the API. You realized you might not have
the admin section working yet. You also revisited an older issue about countries
being listed twice in your data and looked at the GoatCounter repo to see why.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Personal tools and privacy&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We discussed private movement trackers for GrapheneOS, and you settled on &lt;em&gt;PFA&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; as
a lightweight way to track steps and distance without leaking data.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Side notes&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You mentioned two new blog posts being live -- &lt;em&gt;Transit Tracker in Discourse&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; and
&lt;em&gt;Yak&#x27;s Virtual Currency - Part 2&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; -- both updated with screenshots.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      <item>
          <title>ChatGPT assisted Changelog - 41&#x2F;52</title>
          <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Unknown</author>
          <link>https://jakegoldsborough.com/blog/2025/weekly-summary-41/</link>
          <guid>https://jakegoldsborough.com/blog/2025/weekly-summary-41/</guid>
          <description xml:base="https://jakegoldsborough.com/blog/2025/weekly-summary-41/">&lt;p&gt;This week centered on publishing, polishing, and reflecting on your Discourse
work, with some light data analysis and side discussions along the way.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Blog and Writing&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You published &lt;em&gt;&quot;Building a Live Transit Departure Board with Discourse&quot;&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, a
follow-up to your earlier post about your first Discourse core contribution.
The piece explored how you built a live transit tracker plugin that reimagines
Discourse as a real-time data board rather than a forum. You asked if posting
it on the official Discourse blog would be weird, ultimately deciding it would
make sense given your role there. You also asked if the piece itself was
interesting -- it was, both technically and conceptually, tying in your love of
open data and infrastructure with your day job.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data and Analytics&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You dug into your GoatCounter analytics, examining visitor distribution across
countries. After cleaning up duplicate entries, you found &lt;strong&gt;37 unique countries&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;
represented, spanning &lt;strong&gt;six continents&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; -- North America, South America, Europe,
Asia, Africa, and Oceania. Europe and Asia were the strongest regions overall.
The data was reformatted into a clean markdown table for future reference.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Open Source and Development&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You briefly noted another bug you found in the AWS SDK for Ruby, following your
previous fix and contribution, reinforcing your growing involvement in that
project&#x27;s ecosystem.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overall&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a quieter week but a meaningful one -- marked by the satisfaction of
publishing a well-crafted post that blends creativity and engineering. The
analytics work helped ground your readership data, while your continued OSS
engagement kept your technical momentum going.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      <item>
          <title>ChatGPT assisted Changelog - 40&#x2F;52</title>
          <pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Unknown</author>
          <link>https://jakegoldsborough.com/blog/2025/weekly-summary-40/</link>
          <guid>https://jakegoldsborough.com/blog/2025/weekly-summary-40/</guid>
          <description xml:base="https://jakegoldsborough.com/blog/2025/weekly-summary-40/">&lt;p&gt;The week covered a mix of practical, technical, and personal topics.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;travel-and-residency&quot;&gt;Travel and Residency&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discussions continued around moving to Czechia. You asked about employer
documents, contracts, the passport biopage, tax implications, accommodation
requirements, and realistic timelines for when you could start working from
Prague. Flatio was identified as a likely short-term housing option.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;anki-and-language-learning&quot;&gt;Anki and Language Learning&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You set up an Anki deck for learning Czech. The focus was on the alphabet,
pronunciation, and use of IPA symbols. We went through how to structure the
deck, what templates should look like, and clarified things like vowel length.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;nixos-and-framework-issues&quot;&gt;NixOS and Framework Issues&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were troubleshooting sessions with your Framework 16 and NixOS. Problems
included the command key breaking after an RGB reset, the RGB matrix not working
in Linux, and questions about whether this tied to a NixOS upgrade. We looked at
inputmodule installation, what parts of &#x2F;etc are declarative, and the Framework
warranty&#x2F;return policy.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;broader-nixos-community&quot;&gt;Broader NixOS Community&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You asked about the NixOS steering committee drama and its connection to
Anduril, looking for current context on community governance issues.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;practical-life-logistics&quot;&gt;Practical Life Logistics&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few everyday topics came up:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Steps for getting a car repaired after being rear-ended.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to cancel a Moda healthcare plan.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Best backup plan when changing operating systems.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Selling an old car (1974 Ford Ranchero) in Portland, with estimates for repair
or restoration and whether shops do at-home consultations.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;projects-and-ideas&quot;&gt;Projects and Ideas&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You continued brainstorming unique Discourse plugin ideas. This included using
Discourse to track flights, trains, or transit legs (with Prague trams as a test
case) and asking about APIs and boilerplate plugin setup.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;miscellaneous&quot;&gt;Miscellaneous&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GoatCounter analytics and why a single link share might register multiple
views (including prefetching behavior).&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Color distribution analysis on an uploaded image, with rotations and
measurements.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;iPad Mini use cases.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Services to help sell or donate items at home.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shipping personal items from the US to Europe.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kastaplast first run disc valuations and market prices, including Falk, Lots,
Stål, Göte, Berg, and Reko.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, the week balanced ongoing emigration planning and language study with
NixOS troubleshooting, plugin experiments, and practical life logistics.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      <item>
          <title>ChatGPT assisted Changelog - 36-39&#x2F;52</title>
          <pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Unknown</author>
          <link>https://jakegoldsborough.com/blog/2025/weekly-summary-36/</link>
          <guid>https://jakegoldsborough.com/blog/2025/weekly-summary-36/</guid>
          <description xml:base="https://jakegoldsborough.com/blog/2025/weekly-summary-36/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Travel and Prague notes&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A first Europe trip to Prague sparked a travel post and follow ups. Sections
about the castle, tram lines 6 and 17, and Czech Cubism were drafted. Airport
and TSA logistics were covered, including CT scanner lanes at PDX, KLM meal
expectations, missed connection handling at AMS, and return routing via JFK.
Mint Mobile&#x27;s international pass proved sufficient for a week, with OsmAnd
recommended for offline maps and Obtainium used to install apps without Play
Store.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Czech visa preparation&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Residency planning continued. A rental listing in Holesovice prompted an email
draft to the agent and an explanation of Czech 4+1 flat notation. Resources for
US to CZ expats, the role of Flatio, timing without a fixed move date, and
document prep were explored. An employer affidavit template was rewritten in
plain text. Fingerprinting and FBI background check expectations were
clarified. Czech terms like software engineer and contract types such as HPP
were noted.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cameras and creative gear&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beginner travel camera options were compared: Nikon Z30 and Canon R50 kits
versus the Ricoh GRIII for street and night work. Strengths, tradeoffs, and
lens choices were outlined. For carry systems, compact bags and local stock for
brands like WANDRD were discussed, with an eye toward minimal kits.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Discourse experiments and ideas&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A flurry of off label Discourse concepts landed, from non forum app patterns to
playful ideas like Conway&#x27;s Game of Life. Practicalities came up too: VPS disk
pressure from journal files, running locally instead, and revisiting plugin
basics. A specific plugin that tracks days until the next cake day was analyzed
for implementation details and feasibility.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Desktop tooling and small wins&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Wayland, grim plus wl copy needed an explicit MIME type to fix clipboard
issues. A Nushell function location was clarified, and a prompt flow was added
to optionally save screenshots after copying. Hyprland confirmations and UX
touches resurfaced as blog worthy tips.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Selling, shipping, and decluttering&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paths for selling a non running 1974 Ford Ranchero in Portland were mapped out:
where to get initial consultations, rough cost expectations for engine checks
and tune ups, and whether restoration would raise sale value. Services that
help sell or donate household items were listed. Options for shipping personal
goods from the US to Europe were compared at a high level.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Email deliverability and DNS&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Email headers were unpacked for a non technical audience. DKIM and DMARC were
explained in plain terms, realistic DNS propagation timing was set, and common
DMARC failure causes were reviewed. The idea of account warming was addressed
with a pragmatic lens. Header domains and alignment details were parsed from
sample Authentication Results lines.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disc golf market checks&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kastaplast first run prices were researched with a focus on Falk, Lots, Stal,
and Gote. Market ranges, recency caveats, and condition effects were noted. A
correction landed for the Reko mix, with early plastics clarified. A well used
FR Berg valuation was discussed with realism about wear and ceiling prices.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Personal finance and admin&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;401k choices were outlined: cash out implications, rollovers to IRAs, and how a
move abroad intersects with taxes and planning. Help from fiduciary advisors
and any digital nomad friendly country programs were surveyed at a high level.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Logos, apps, and posts&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A map based Loop Finder app concept took shape using Vue, with local
GraphHopper via Docker Compose to remove API key friction. Zola templating for
shared resume layouts was explored. A prior post on typing Swedish with a US
keyboard kept attracting search traffic.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Housekeeping on the site&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Styling for headings aimed at mobile readability while respecting an 80 char
column. Prior weekly summaries stayed the model: plain text markdown, no fancy
chars, prose first, and wrapped lines. Future posts were queued from several
threads above, especially Prague transport notes, Hyprland prompts, and the
email DNS explainer.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      <item>
          <title>ChatGPT assisted Changelog - 35&#x2F;52</title>
          <pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Unknown</author>
          <link>https://jakegoldsborough.com/blog/2025/weekly-summary-35/</link>
          <guid>https://jakegoldsborough.com/blog/2025/weekly-summary-35/</guid>
          <description xml:base="https://jakegoldsborough.com/blog/2025/weekly-summary-35/">&lt;p&gt;This week covered a mix of personal projects, resume updates, and site tweaks.
On the budgeting front, cashctl planning continued, with refinements to the
workflow around paydays, file naming, and how income gets assigned to periods.
Simulated paycheck commands and outputs were discussed to bring the tool closer
to being usable.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Work on the personal site also came up. A Zola question about sharing one resume
template across multiple pages was raised, along with CSS improvements for
headings that stay mobile friendly while keeping within an 80-character layout.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Resume polish was another theme. A contribution to the AWS SDK for Ruby was
turned into a resume-style entry, with placement under the Discourse role
considered for now. Additional feedback was asked for on how to position open
source work.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The node-postgres-exporter project also got a GitHub star, and further
improvements were considered, such as in-memory caching and local storage to
smooth over network blips.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was also some lighter talk--identifying a pine tree, considering Vermont
properties, and chatting about power adapters and credit scores.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, the week blended cashctl development, resume building, static site
refinements, and a bit of infrastructure and personal exploration.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      <item>
          <title>ChatGPT assisted Changelog - 34&#x2F;52</title>
          <pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Unknown</author>
          <link>https://jakegoldsborough.com/blog/2025/weekly-summary-34/</link>
          <guid>https://jakegoldsborough.com/blog/2025/weekly-summary-34/</guid>
          <description xml:base="https://jakegoldsborough.com/blog/2025/weekly-summary-34/">&lt;p&gt;This week balanced travel research, disc golf writing edits, technical
debugging, and creative design work. On the travel side, questions came up
about flying with  money internationally and how ATM fees
might look in the Czech Republic with an OnPoint credit union card. You also
researched the best European power adapters, checking Wirecutter&#x27;s
recommendations for reliable options.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Shelltrax, you continued to refine autoplay. The &lt;code&gt;play_next_track&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; function
was revisited to keep the footer showing artist and song info, just as before.
The main issue left was that the progress bar didn&#x27;t carry over correctly
between tracks when autoplay advanced.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the creative side, you explored what the Discourse logo might look like if
it had aged 100 years, and separately, how it could be reimagined if the
company had started as a penpal or letter-writing business. Both ideas fit into
your broader exploration of branding experiments.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Swedish (and some German) study streak has been extended to 239 days in a
row.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, the week tied together preparations for international travel, cleanup
work on ongoing projects, and a mix of technical and creative problem-solving.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      <item>
          <title>ChatGPT assisted Changelog - 32+33&#x2F;52</title>
          <pubDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Unknown</author>
          <link>https://jakegoldsborough.com/blog/2025/weekly-summary-32-33/</link>
          <guid>https://jakegoldsborough.com/blog/2025/weekly-summary-32-33/</guid>
          <description xml:base="https://jakegoldsborough.com/blog/2025/weekly-summary-32-33/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Early August Projects&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first week of August was centered on your Node-postgres-exporter work.
You finished the conversion to ESM and TypeScript and started thinking about
next steps. Around the same time, you were also looking into writing a Nix
package for Discourse, asking how to handle complex setups that involve
databases and services.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;System and Config Troubles&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A fair amount of time went into NixOS. You ran into an error with
&lt;code&gt;nixos-option&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; and flakes not being found in &lt;code&gt;.config&#x2F;nix&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;, and later were
debugging Git commit signing issues (wrong email in the commit vs author
fields). You also asked about forcing Git to use a certain SSH key or email
per repo. Other NixOS topics included setting up Wi-Fi on your Framework 16,
writing custom modules (like for Kolide), installing packages for Python and
Ruby in nix-shell, and configuring Starship with Nushell.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hardware and Devices&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You were troubleshooting Librewolf not showing your Bluetooth headset mic,
plus issues with Wi-Fi and Ethernet modules on the Framework. There was also
a question about pinentry not working with GPG on NixOS. On the hardware
front, you asked about pixel misalignment on your monitor and learned about
TCON as a possible cause.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lifestyle and Planning&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You asked about FSAs and their use. Travel came up too, with your upcoming
Europe trip and looking  for the best power adapters (especially for the Czech
Republic).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Blogging and Writing&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your NixOS daily driver series continued, with a post on getting Wi-Fi
working on the Framework 16. You considered what direction to take the next
entry. You also asked for an intro&#x2F;about section to describe yourself,
condensing it down to 5 sentences. In parallel, you&#x27;ve kept up with weekly
summaries and changelog-style posts.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Miscellaneous&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other threads included practicing Terraform and Nomad, CSS layout questions,
and making Hyprland keybinds prompt for confirmation before closing a window.
On the wearable side, your PineTime step counter broke and you asked about
firmware, Gadgetbridge, and even writing your own step-tracking app in Rust
or Kotlin.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      <item>
          <title>ChatGPT assisted Changelog - 31&#x2F;52</title>
          <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Unknown</author>
          <link>https://jakegoldsborough.com/blog/2025/weekly-summary-31/</link>
          <guid>https://jakegoldsborough.com/blog/2025/weekly-summary-31/</guid>
          <description xml:base="https://jakegoldsborough.com/blog/2025/weekly-summary-31/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nix package development&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We discussed writing a Nix package for a complex project with multiple
resources, using the Discourse install-cloud guide as a template to structure
derivations and manage dependencies cleanly.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NixOS Wi-Fi on Framework 16&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We troubleshooted nmcli reporting the Intel AX210 as DOWN, enabled wireless in
configuration.nix, and resolved common pitfalls to bring up the wireless
interface successfully.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Git commit signing&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We covered forcing Git to use a specific SSH key for a given repository, how to
resign commits, and how to update the commit email so that signatures appear
valid.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hyprland keybinds&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We added a custom Hyprland keybind to close the active window with a
confirmation dialog, and refined the yes&#x2F;no prompts and dialog appearance for
better usability.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Terraform and Nomad learning&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We explored practical resources--sample projects, tutorials, and sandbox
environments--to build hands-on experience with Terraform and Nomad
orchestration.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bluetooth audio input&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We investigated why LibreWolf failed to detect a Bluetooth headset mic,
including how to identify the board, check firmware versions, and verify
driver support.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Email server on NixOS&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We outlined setting up a mail server on NixOS and using Caddy to automate TLS
certificate issuance for secure SMTP and IMAP provisioning.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Privacy-focused smartwatches&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We reviewed open-source options like the PineTime, diagnosed step-counter
failures, checked return policies, and sketched a plan for a Rust-based long-
term step tracker integrated with Gadgetbridge.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Swedish Studies&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;221 days in a row on Babbel. Listened to audio books as well this week.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      <item>
          <title>ChatGPT assisted Changelog - 30&#x2F;52</title>
          <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Unknown</author>
          <link>https://jakegoldsborough.com/blog/2025/weekly-summary-30/</link>
          <guid>https://jakegoldsborough.com/blog/2025/weekly-summary-30/</guid>
          <description xml:base="https://jakegoldsborough.com/blog/2025/weekly-summary-30/">&lt;h3 id=&quot;tech&quot;&gt;Tech&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Waybar network module&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discussions on adding an ethernet or wifi status module to Waybar
configuration for Hyprland in NixOS.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nixvim branch specification&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Explored how to pin a specific branch in nixvim and how imports resolve
relative paths in modular NixOS configs.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kolide nix-agent on NixOS&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reviewed non-flake-based Kolide agent setup, module imports, time zone
settings, and troubleshooting import errors.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Responsive CSS patterns&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Covered CSS techniques for responsive background images and use of the
&lt;code&gt;:before&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; pseudo-element to style boxes.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TUI music player pause fix&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Debugged keybinding logic in the Rust TUI music player, refining
toggle_pause behavior to eliminate extra keystrokes.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Arch Linux vs NixOS installation&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Compared archinstall features, encryption support, and filesystem choices
(btrfs vs ext4); discussed backup and fallback strategies.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wi-Fi and GPG in NixOS&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Troubleshooted wifi connections via NetworkManager, git commit email
issues, and GPG pinentry failures in a NixOS environment.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SSH key management&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Advised on forcing Git to use specific SSH keys per repository and
evaluated ed25519 as the default key type.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Starship prompt in NixOS and Nushell&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Installed and configured Starship in NixOS, and explored Nushell integration.
Need to fix path in Nushell.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Python and Ruby in nix-shell&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Set up nix-shell with Python packages, managed Ruby gems, and fixed
pinentry and gemdir errors within shellHook workarounds.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;personal&quot;&gt;Personal&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First Week at Discourse!&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The onboarding process has been very smooth and everyone is very welcoming. I am
excited about my future there.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Swedish&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;215 days in a row.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      <item>
          <title>ChatGPT assisted Changelog - 29&#x2F;52</title>
          <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Unknown</author>
          <link>https://jakegoldsborough.com/blog/2025/weekly-summary-29/</link>
          <guid>https://jakegoldsborough.com/blog/2025/weekly-summary-29/</guid>
          <description xml:base="https://jakegoldsborough.com/blog/2025/weekly-summary-29/">&lt;h3 id=&quot;nixos-daily-driver-and-dotfiles&quot;&gt;NixOS Daily Driver and Dotfiles&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Continued refining NixOS setup and daily driver blog series&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Modularized dotfiles using Dotter with template support&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adopted approach of letting NixOS generate base config, layering custom on top&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explored idea of a &quot;LazyNix&quot; dev toolkit using importable modules&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Troubleshot and resolved GRUB and UEFI encryption setup issues&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;framework-laptop-and-qmk-customization&quot;&gt;Framework Laptop and QMK Customization&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New laptop! Framework 16&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Investigated Framework RGB keyboard and LED matrix customization&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Confirmed QMK support and existence of Rust libraries (most tooling is in C)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Searched for examples and guides to interact with Framework&#x27;s LED module&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;task-management-and-productivity-tools&quot;&gt;Task Management and Productivity Tools&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Looked into Rust-based TUI task managers like Taskwarrior&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reviewed Taskwarrior features like due dates, tags, and urgency scoring&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Practiced adding and updating tasks with CLI syntax&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;git-and-hosting&quot;&gt;Git and Hosting&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Managing personal site using two remotes, pushing to both for now&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Long-term plan is to self-host once everything is working reliably&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;nixcon-2025-planning&quot;&gt;NixCon 2025 Planning&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Would like to attend NixCon in Rapperswil-Jona, Sept 5 to 7&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;avatars-and-stickers&quot;&gt;Avatars and Stickers&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tweaked Tux-human avatar&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Looked for places to buy open source stickers that support the projects&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;neovim-fonts-and-waybar&quot;&gt;Neovim, Fonts, and Waybar&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set up Nixvim to remove trailing whitespace on save&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Troubleshot font issue in WezTerm by refreshing font cache and restarting&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Created toggleable Waybar for system stats using manual launch approach&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;language-learning&quot;&gt;Language Learning&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;210 days of Swedish in a row&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trying to pick some German back up for trip to Prague&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      <item>
          <title>ChatGPT assisted Changelog - 28&#x2F;52</title>
          <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Unknown</author>
          <link>https://jakegoldsborough.com/blog/2025/weekly-summary-28/</link>
          <guid>https://jakegoldsborough.com/blog/2025/weekly-summary-28/</guid>
          <description xml:base="https://jakegoldsborough.com/blog/2025/weekly-summary-28/">&lt;h3 id=&quot;20250704-20250711&quot;&gt;20250704 - 20250711&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;cyberspace&quot;&gt;Cyberspace&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;nixos&quot;&gt;NixOS&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Published two posts in Daily Driver series. My late 2011 Macbook Pro running
NixOs is already feeling ready for daily use really:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;&#x2F;blog&#x2F;2025&#x2F;nixos-daily-driver-5&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Part 5&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;&#x2F;blog&#x2F;2025&#x2F;nixos-daily-driver-6&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Part 6&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fighting encrypted disk installation. Installation seems fine but then I can&#x27;t
unlock drive to boot up.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;meatspace&quot;&gt;Meatspace&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;disc-golf&quot;&gt;Disc Golf&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Played Pier Park&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Played Memorial Park&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Published post about experience with UDisc regarding my open source library:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;&#x2F;blog&#x2F;2025&#x2F;fairway-client-not-fair-enough&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Fairway Client Not Fair Enough&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;language-studies&quot;&gt;Language Studies&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Swedish&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;204 day streak on Babbel. Did a few more lessons this week and not just
review. Listened to some Radio Sweden på lätt Svenska (Radio Sweden in easy
Swedish)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Czech&#x2F;German&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I found out I&#x27;ll be going to Prague in Sept so I may try to pick up a little
Czech and brush up on German as many speak it there apparently.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;garden&quot;&gt;Garden&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Harvested 3 squash&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blueberry bush is fruiting&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Raspberry bush is flowering&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tomatoes are flowering&#x2F;growing&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New tomato and pepper starts are doing well&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;music&quot;&gt;Music&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Listened to a lot of Top Dawg Entertainment this week - Kendrick Lamar,
Ab-Soul, Doechii, Schoolboy-Q&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      <item>
          <title>ChatGPT Changelog - 27&#x2F;52</title>
          <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Unknown</author>
          <link>https://jakegoldsborough.com/blog/2025/weekly-summary-27/</link>
          <guid>https://jakegoldsborough.com/blog/2025/weekly-summary-27/</guid>
          <description xml:base="https://jakegoldsborough.com/blog/2025/weekly-summary-27/">&lt;h3 id=&quot;nixos-nixvim-work&quot;&gt;NixOS &amp;amp; NixVim Work&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed issues with &lt;code&gt;interception&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; and remapping caps lock to esc on tap
and ctrl on hold&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Investigated how to migrate from LazyVim to NixVim in a non-flake setup and
how to modularize configuration.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Installed Starship and worked through integration with Nushell on NixOS,
resolving autocomplete issues related to Carapace and Fish.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PipeWire was installed and CLI methods for inspecting its settings were
explored.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Requested a developer-friendly NixVim config with completions and LSP support
for both Node.js and Rust.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compared nix-shell and flakes, with interest in setting up per-project
environments for tools like Zola, Node, and Rust.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;udisc-reverse-engineering&quot;&gt;UDisc Reverse Engineering&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Public GitHub repo and blog posts were removed following a takedown request
from UDisc. Redacted versions will be reposted later.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;etsy-and-woodworking&quot;&gt;Etsy and Woodworking&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added chunky maple cooking utensil&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added 4 piece mixed hardwood coaster set&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Working on utensil rest&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Working on guitar body&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;personal&quot;&gt;Personal&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Swedish learning streak hit 198 days&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Received an offer letter!&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      <item>
          <title>ChatGPT Changelog (fka Weekly Summary) - 26&#x2F;52</title>
          <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Unknown</author>
          <link>https://jakegoldsborough.com/blog/2025/weekly-summary-26/</link>
          <guid>https://jakegoldsborough.com/blog/2025/weekly-summary-26/</guid>
          <description xml:base="https://jakegoldsborough.com/blog/2025/weekly-summary-26/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;nixos-workflow-improvements&quot;&gt;NixOS Workflow &amp;amp; Improvements&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Refined NixOS development workflow by exploring the use of &lt;code&gt;nix-shell&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;
and Flakes for environment isolation and reproducibility. Discussed how to
structure shell files for separate projects (e.g. Rust&#x2F;Zola vs. Node).&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discovered how tools like &lt;code&gt;rustup&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;volta&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; behave in Nix environments.
You acknowledged that &lt;code&gt;nix-shell&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; helps contain them safely, but the
Nix-native approach may still be preferable long term.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cleaned up a bug with &lt;code&gt;nixvim&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; setup by updating to the latest
version and resolving a plugin rename (&lt;code&gt;coedium-vim&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; ➝ &lt;code&gt;windsurf&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;).&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added Blueman via Nix, and experimented with different ways to start Waybar
without tying up terminal (eventually using &lt;code&gt;hyprctl dispatch exec&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;).&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Successfully reversed trackpad scroll direction in Hyprland using overrides,
and this worked well across setup.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;gitvote-gpg-work&quot;&gt;GitVote &amp;amp; GPG Work&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Progressed &lt;code&gt;gitvote&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; CLI and backend significantly:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implemented registration and GPG signature support.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Verified that voting model and simulation strategy still worked.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explored commit signing, storing keys in-repo, and ensuring modular CLI
support for different user flows.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Began planning for how to handle edge cases like simultaneous votes and
eventually tallying.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;blogging-writing&quot;&gt;Blogging &amp;amp; Writing&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Continued work on NixOS daily driver series, planning to document how to
set up Dotter and Hyprland cleanly from scratch before layering more config.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reflected on privacy-focused analytics post, considering how to improve
tracking and discussing stance on respecting blockers.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;udisc-api-wrapper-library&quot;&gt;UDisc API &amp;amp; Wrapper Library&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Worked on orchestration pattern for the TypeScript &lt;code&gt;UDiscAPI&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; class,
ensuring everything flows through a clean and testable interface.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Removed unnecessary &lt;code&gt;loadFromFile&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; logic and moved toward using raw JSON
inputs with explicit route extraction.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Streamlined the construction flow:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;pre style=&quot;background-color:#2b303b;color:#c0c5ce;&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span&gt;const udisc = new UDisc();
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;const schemaMap = udisc.extractSchemaMap(raw);
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;const eventListings = udisc.resolveKeyValuePairs(&amp;#39;eventListing&amp;#39;);
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;pre&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;personal-progress&quot;&gt;Personal Progress&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maintained streak of learning Swedish — now at 193 days in a row. Mostly
review. Need to listen to more podcasts&#x2F;books again.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Only played one round of disc golf this week&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      <item>
          <title>ChatGPT Changelog (fka Weekly Summary) - 25&#x2F;52</title>
          <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Unknown</author>
          <link>https://jakegoldsborough.com/blog/2025/weekly-summary-25/</link>
          <guid>https://jakegoldsborough.com/blog/2025/weekly-summary-25/</guid>
          <description xml:base="https://jakegoldsborough.com/blog/2025/weekly-summary-25/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;weekly-summary-2025-06-13-to-2025-06-20&quot;&gt;Weekly Summary — 2025-06-13 to 2025-06-20&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;accomplishments&quot;&gt;Accomplishments&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;shelltrax-tui&quot;&gt;Shelltrax TUI&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Continued refinement of Shelltrax (TUI music player).&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Autoplay behavior adjustments: added logic to handle album track advancement.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Made progress on Symphonia integration for FLAC and seeking support.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;open-udisc-api&quot;&gt;open-udisc-api&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Further decoding work on Remix-style &lt;code&gt;.data&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; format.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Continued schema-indexed record handling.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Published part 4 of your UDisc reverse engineering blog series.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Meta post idea evolving for later publication.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;node-postgres-exporter&quot;&gt;node-postgres-exporter&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Built a lightweight &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;ducks&#x2F;node-postgres-exporter&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;node-postgres-exporter&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for Prometheus.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;nixos&quot;&gt;NixOS&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ongoing modular NixOS configuration improvements.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TTY-first daily driver series is slowly building up. New post soon.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;swedish-studies&quot;&gt;Swedish studies&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hit 186 days in a row on Babbel.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Published “Typing Swedish with US Keyboard” blog post.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;todos&quot;&gt;TODOs&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;shelltrax-tui-1&quot;&gt;ShellTrax TUI&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix footer (currently doesn&#x27;t update with next song, and progress is not perfect)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix broken metadata parsing&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;open-udisc-api-1&quot;&gt;open-udisc-api&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Figure out what post 5 should be about&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;nixos-1&quot;&gt;NixOS&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write next post about hyprland and other config updates&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;swedish-studies-1&quot;&gt;Swedish studies&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Listen to more audiobooks this week&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do more than bare minimum reviews&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      <item>
          <title>ChatGPT Changelog (fka Weekly Summary) - 24&#x2F;52</title>
          <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Unknown</author>
          <link>https://jakegoldsborough.com/blog/2025/weekly-summary-24/</link>
          <guid>https://jakegoldsborough.com/blog/2025/weekly-summary-24/</guid>
          <description xml:base="https://jakegoldsborough.com/blog/2025/weekly-summary-24/">&lt;h3 id=&quot;happy-friday-the-13th&quot;&gt;Happy Friday the 13th!&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have decided to slightly change up my personal weekly summary posts.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been using ChatGPT more and more and really find it to be an important
tool. It saves me so much time with debugging error messages and digging
through docs. It can also keep very good track of what I&#x27;ve been working on
and thinking about. Because of this, I have decided to update the way I do
the weekly summary. I am going to let ChatGPT generate a personal changelog
of everything I have been working on. It&#x27;s not perfect so I do have to edit
it some but it still does a better job than I could ever do.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So with that, here is my weekly ChatGPT changelog:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;accomplishments-since-june-7&quot;&gt;Accomplishments (Since June 7)&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;udisc-api-blog-series&quot;&gt;UDisc API &#x2F; Blog Series&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Published Part 4 of the blog series: deep dive into &lt;code&gt;smartLayouts&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;holes&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved &lt;code&gt;deepHydrate&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;, began resolving issues with arrays of unresolved IDs.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Continued resolving schema-indexed keys (e.g. &lt;code&gt;_254: 270&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;) for clarity.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added blog link to &lt;code&gt;open-udisc-api&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; README.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cleaned up TypeScript types and debugged schema hydration logic.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;infra-devops&quot;&gt;Infra &amp;amp; DevOps&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set up Gitea using a Linux service.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implemented a Git pre-push hook to filter Zola drafts before publishing.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Decided to drop OpenAPI support for the current API project.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;postgresql-exporter&quot;&gt;PostgreSQL Exporter&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deployed a general-purpose PostgreSQL -&amp;gt; Prometheus exporter.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Added &lt;code&gt;&#x2F;metrics&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;&#x2F;livez&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;&#x2F;readyz&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;&#x2F;configz&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; endpoints.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Configured basic token authentication.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Documented endpoints and auth in the README.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;nixos-hyprland&quot;&gt;NixOS &#x2F; Hyprland&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Diagnosed Hyprland reload issues involving &lt;code&gt;exec-once&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; behavior.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Installed and confirmed use of:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;wezterm&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;dunst&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;hypridle&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;bibata-cursor-theme&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explored xcursor previews and how to apply cursor themes via Nix.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set up Waybar with Gruvbox-inspired CSS.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;miscellaneous&quot;&gt;Miscellaneous&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Continued Swedish learning streak (currently 179+ days).&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Expanded concept for a first-person disc golf course viewer.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Researched 360-degree and panoramic photo capture on Android&#x2F;GrapheneOS.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;to-do-improvements&quot;&gt;To-Do &#x2F; Improvements&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;udisc-api-blog&quot;&gt;UDisc API + Blog&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix unresolved arrays in &lt;code&gt;deepHydrate&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;, such as &lt;code&gt;targetPositionLabels&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Begin drafting a &quot;meta&quot; post summarizing the UDisc reverse-engineering series.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write additional parts exploring fields like &lt;code&gt;dogleg&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;obLines&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explore creating a visualizer for hydrated course data.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;infra-self-hosting&quot;&gt;Infra &#x2F; Self-Hosting&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Document the Gitea systemd service setup.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write a blog post about using Git hooks to manage Zola drafts.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;nixos-hyprland-1&quot;&gt;NixOS &#x2F; Hyprland&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Investigate why &lt;code&gt;exec-once&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; commands don&#x27;t rerun on &lt;code&gt;hyprctl reload&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Continue refining modular &lt;code&gt;environment.systemPackages&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; layout.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Extend daily-driver blog series for NixOS on MacBook hardware.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;portfolio-sharing&quot;&gt;Portfolio + Sharing&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add README links or badges to published blog posts.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write a post about decoding custom schema formats in APIs.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Share blog content on Hacker News, Lobsters, or relevant communities.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</description>
      </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
