<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
      <title>Jake Goldsborough - prague</title>
      <link>https://jakegoldsborough.com</link>
      <description></description>
      <generator>Zola</generator>
      <language>en</language>
      <atom:link href="https://jakegoldsborough.com/tags/prague/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
      <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
      <item>
          <title>First time in Europe: One week in Prague</title>
          <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Unknown</author>
          <link>https://jakegoldsborough.com/blog/2025/visiting-prague-first-time-in-europe/</link>
          <guid>https://jakegoldsborough.com/blog/2025/visiting-prague-first-time-in-europe/</guid>
          <description xml:base="https://jakegoldsborough.com/blog/2025/visiting-prague-first-time-in-europe/">&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-country-boy-goes-to-europe&quot;&gt;A Country Boy Goes to Europe&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This past week was the annual global meetup for
&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;discourse.org&quot;&gt;Discourse&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, the company I recently joined. I was lucky
enough to get hired right before the planning cutoff date, and they were very
generous to include me so early in my tenure. That inclusion made me feel
valued and trusted. This year the meetup was held in Prague, Czech Republic.
I was excited because I have never been out of North America.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;initial-leg-and-a-missed-connection-in-amsterdam&quot;&gt;Initial Leg and a Missed Connection in Amsterdam&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The trip started with a flight from Portland to Amsterdam. It was pretty
smooth, even if long. The only real issue was that the flight arrived late.
On top of that, the passport control line in Amsterdam may have been the
longest line I have ever seen in an airport. Those two things combined forced
me to miss my connecting flight to Prague. Luckily I was flying KLM, which is
very good about rebooking a new flight when it is their fault.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had to do &lt;strong&gt;A LOT&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; of walking and waiting, but I got rebooked and made it
to my new flight.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;meeting-my-new-coworkers&quot;&gt;Meeting My New Coworkers&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For all the excitement, I was nervous too. I am introverted, and walking into
a room of about 70 people I did not know was daunting. I am not great at
introducing myself and I do not feel &quot;important&quot; enough to assume people want
to meet me. I was not the only first timer, but I was by far the newest hire.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;prague-castle&quot;&gt;Prague Castle&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prague Castle is not a single building as much as it is a hilltop campus of
courtyards, churches, palaces, and gardens.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;st-vitus-cathedral&quot;&gt;St. Vitus Cathedral&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although I am anti-religion, I can appreciate the architecture of old world
churches. Pictures cannot do this building justice. The height, beauty, and
aging are things you just have to see in person.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;cathedral-1.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;St. Vitus Cathedral, front view&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;cathedral-stained-glass.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;St. Vitus Cathedral stained glass windows&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;golden-lane-zlata-ulicka&quot;&gt;Golden Lane (Zlatá ulička)&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This pocket street sits between the Bílá Tower and Daliborka Tower. The tiny,
colorful houses were built into the castle fortifications around the end of
the 16th century and stayed lived in up to the Second World War. Several of
the homes now show period interiors that trace everyday life on the lane
across five centuries.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;House No. 22 is the best known stop. Franz Kafka stayed here for a time
during the First World War. Facades were repainted in the 1950s following
designs by Jiří Trnka, which is part of why the lane looks so storybook
today.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Climb the steps at House No. 12 to the terrace above Daliborka. The round
tower dates to 1496 and served as a prison until 1781. You will see notes
about the knight Dalibor of Kozojedy, the tower&#x27;s first recorded inmate.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-castle-proper-old-royal-palace&quot;&gt;The Castle Proper (Old Royal Palace)&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Old Royal Palace centers on Vladislav Hall: huge, yet surprisingly open.
The broad Riders&#x27; Staircase was built so horsemen could enter, which says a
lot about the space&#x27;s ambitions. Outside, the courtyards do the real work of
the visit: sit, watch the guard change, and let the pace reset. On the south
side, terraces step down toward the river with quiet garden paths and big sky
views.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;view-from-castle-1.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;View south over Prague from the castle terraces&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;public-trams-it&quot;&gt;Public Trams-it&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prague&#x27;s tram network is part moving museum, part everyday superpower.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A quick history:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1875: horse trams debut in Prague&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1891: inventor František Křižík launches the first electric tram (Letná)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1962: the Tatra T3, the red cream classic, begins service and becomes a
design icon still seen today&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2010s to current: 100% low floor Škoda 15T ForCity sets the modern standard&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I caught almost every ride at Veletržní palác, a 2 minute walk from Mama
Shelter. Lines &lt;strong&gt;6&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;17&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; stop here, so I could either hug the river or
cut across town without thinking too hard. Daytime trams run about every 8 to
20 minutes, so it felt like show up and go.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;tram-6&quot;&gt;Tram 6&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Line 6 connects Nádraží Holešovice to Kubánské náměstí, which makes it a
useful cross town link if you are moving between Holešovice, the center, and
Vršovice. Daytime trams in Prague typically run every 8 to 20 minutes, so you
can treat both 6 and 17 like show up and go service.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;tram-17&quot;&gt;Tram 17&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Line 17 hugs the Vltava for long stretches, so it is the easy, scenic way to
glide past Národní divadlo, Staroměstská, Výtoň, and the riverfront. It links
the north (Vozovna Kobylisy) with the south (Sídliště Modřany and Libuš). If
you want a view rich ride, sit by the window on this one.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;czech-cubist-museum-at-the-house-of-the-black-madonna&quot;&gt;Czech Cubist Museum at The House of the Black Madonna&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Czech Cubism did not stop at the canvas. It leapt into architecture,
furniture, and everyday objects. One of the movement&#x27;s showpieces is located
at The House at the Black Madonna, which was built in 1911 to 1912 and
designed by Josef Gočár. It was a Cubist designed department store turned
cultural landmark of Old Town. Today it hosts The Museum of Czech Cubism and
a restored Grand Cafe Orient.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;cubist-illustration.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Czech Cubist poster&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;cubist-bench.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Czech Cubist bench&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;cubist-couch.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Czech Cubist couch&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;cubist-chair.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Czech Cubist chair&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;permanent-souvenirs&quot;&gt;Permanent Souvenirs&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to get a couple permanent souvenirs in the form of tattoos while
there.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;dario-squirrel.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Squirrel grabbing nuts, blackwork tattoo&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tattoo by &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;dario_kristoffersen&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Dario Kristoffersen&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; at &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.onelovetattoo.cz&#x2F;tattooers&#x2F;dario-kristoffersen&quot;&gt;One Love Tattoo&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.
Prague, 2025.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;tarlito-praha-castle.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Prague Castle, blackwork tattoo&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tattoo by &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.instagram.com&#x2F;tarlito&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Tarlito&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; at &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.onelovetattoo.cz&#x2F;tattooers&#x2F;tarlito&quot;&gt;One Love Tattoo&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. Prague,
2025.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;summary-and-reflection&quot;&gt;Summary and Reflection&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was honestly the best trip of my life. I absolutely loved Prague and that
old European energy. There was something different in the air. To me, it feels
like a smaller, older New York City.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I loved it so much that I have already started a checklist for a digital nomad
work visa. I could see going back for longer periods to visit and work. I
regret not going to the transit museum, so that is high on the list for the
next visit.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Děkuji, že jste si to přečetli.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
